CIFAR-10 is a popular dataset of 60,000 tiny images,
CIFAR-10 是一个很热门的数据集 其中包含 60,000 张小图
each depicting an object from one of 10 classes.
共分成 10 个类别 每张图都描绘了一个对象
You can see that each image is truly tiny.
可以看出每张图都很小
Only 32 pixels high and wide.
宽和高只有 32 个像素
These are color images so they're interpreted by the computer as
它们是彩色图像 所以计算机将它们解析为
arrays with a depth of three for RGB color channels.
深度为 3 的数组 3 表示 RGB 颜色通道
Because these are color images and there are a lot of them,
因为它们是彩色图像并且有很多
the first thing I'm going to show you is an option to use a GPU for training.
所以首先我将演示如何使用 GPU 训练模型
A GPU is essentially something that allows you to do
GPU 使你能够并行地处理数据
data processing in parallel and so it may prove useful to speed up your training time.
所以也许能够缩短训练时间
Here, you can see I'm loading in my usual libraries and then
我在这里照常加载库
PyTorch gives us a way to check if a GPU device is available.
PyTorch 提供了一种检测是否有可用 GPU 设备的方式
Torch.cuda is available will return a Boolean
torch.cuda.is_available 将返回布尔值true 或 false
variable true or false whether or not a GPU is available.
表示 GPU 设备是否可用
We'll store this and then later if we do have a GPU available will be
我们将存储该变量 之后当 GPU 可用时
able to move our data and our model to that device for faster training.
我们能够将数据和模型移到该设备上并加快训练
For now, I'm just going to visualize some data and present this problem and so I'm using
暂时我将可视化数据并演示该问题 所以我将使用笔记本电脑
my laptop and when I run this cell you can see that I'm training on CPU.
当我运行此单元格时 可以看出我是在 CPU 上训练
Later, when I do try to develop a solution and train a model,
稍后 当我尝试开发解决方案并训练模型时
I'll switch to GPU and in general this is a good thing to know how to use.
我将切换到 GPU 这是通常的做法
Next, I'm going to load in my data as usual.
接下来我将照常加载数据
CIFAR, much like is Amnest is available in the torchvision datasets library.
和 MNIST 很像   CIFAR 也位于 torchvision datasets 库中
I'm going to define my training and my test data by calling datasets.CIFAR10.
我将通过调用 datasets.CIFAR10 定义训练和测试数据
I'll also transform this data into a tensor datatype and normalize
此外 将此数据转换为张量数据类型并标准化 RGB 值
the RGB values so that the pixel values are in a range from about zero to one.
以便像素值的范围是在 0 到 1 之间
Finally, I can load in my transform data in batches using PyTorch's data loader class.
最后 使用 PyTorch 的 DataLoader 类按批次加载转换的数据
These lines of code should look very similar to
这几行代码应该看起来和 MNIST 代码很像
the Amnest code in which we loaded in data,
我们加载了数据
transformed it into a tensor datatype,
转换为张量数据类型
and separated the data into training,
将数据划分为训练集
validation, and test sets.
验证集和测试集
Also down here, I'm specifying the 10 image classes that I'm reading in.
然后在下面指定要读取的 10 个图像类别
All CIFAR-10 images will fall into one of these categories.
所有 CIFAR-10 图像都将属于其中一个类别
The data may take a moment to load in but once
数据加载可能需要一段时间
you load it in you can visualize a batch of that data.
加载之后 你可以可视化一批数据
Here, I've defined a helper function which will basically unnormalize the images
我在这里定义了一个辅助函数 它会取消标准化图像
and convert them from a tensor image type to a non-py image type for visualization,
并将它们从张量图像类型转换为 NumPy 图像类型以进行可视化
then I'm just going to load in and display a batch of
然后加载并显示一批数据
images and here we can verify that these images look pretty much how you would expect.
从这里可以看出图像看起来和我们预期的一样
We have images of cats,
这些图像包括猫
frogs, deer, and automobiles.
青蛙 小鹿和汽车
We can even choose to view an image in more detail.
甚至可以更详细地查看图像
Here, I'm displaying the red, green,
我将一个图像的红绿蓝颜色通道
and blue color channels as grayscale values for one single image and we should again
显示为灰阶值
see that the brightest pixel values are close to
应该会看到最亮的像素值接近 1
the value one and darker ones closer to zero.
更暗的像素值接近 0
Next, you'll want to define and train a CNN to classify these images.
接下来 你需要定义并训练 CNN 分类这些图像
You're also welcome to try out an MLP approach,
你也可以尝试 MLP 方法
see how both work, and compare the results.
看看二者的效果并加以比较
I'll be assuming that you want to define a CNN architecture so I provided
假定你想定义 CNN 架构
links to the documentation for convolutional and maxpooling layers in PyTorch.
我们提供了 PyTorch 卷积层和最大池化层的文档链接
Here's also a simple diagram showing how
这个示例图表显示了
an input image might pass through a couple of these layers.
输入图像如何经过这几个层级
Then if you scroll down,
向下滚动
you can see that I've defined one example convolutional layer for you.
你会发现我为你定义了一个示例卷积层
I've defined it in the init function of our network.
我在网络的 init 函数中定义了该卷积层
To define a convolutional layer,
要定义卷积层
I use nn.Conv2d and I pass in some parameters.
我调用了 nn.Conv2d 并传入一些参数
For our first convolutional layer,
对于第一个卷积层
this will be the number of inputs seen as the depth of the input image.
这个参数将是输入图像的深度
Recall that our inputs are 32 by 32 images with a depth of three for RGB color channels.
输入是 32x32 图像 深度是 3 表示 RGB 颜色通道
So, I've defined the input and I've specified that this
所以将该输入设为 3
should output a convolutional layer with a depth of 16.
并指定输出卷积层的深度应该为 16
That means this layer should take in our image and produce 16 filtered images as output.
表示该层应该接受输入图像并生成 16 个过滤图像
I've also specified that I'm using filters that are 3 by 3 in
同时指定过滤器大小是 3x2
size and to keep my output layer the same x y size as my input image,
为了让输出层的 x,y 大小和输入图像的一样
I'll add one pixel of padding on the border.
我将边界填充设为一个像素
I've also defined one maxpooling layer named pool.
我还定义了一个最大池化层 称为 pool
This has a kernel size and stride size of two which means that any input it's
核大小和步长为 2
applied to it will downsample it x y dimensions by a factor of two.
表示会将任何输入的 x,y 维度下采样到一半大小
Then in the forward function,
然后在 forward 函数中
we can see how all of these things fit together.
将所有这一切组合到一起
For an input image x,
对于输入图像 x
I first pass it into
首先将其传入第一个卷积层
our first convolutional layer and I apply a relu activation function.
并应用 ReLu 激活函数
This output will be passed to a final pooling layer resulting in
将这个输出传入最后的池化层
a downsampled transformed x which I'll return.
生成并返回被下采样的转换后 x
To complete this model,
要完成此模型
it will be up to you to add multiple convolutional and pooling layers and finally
你需要添加多个卷积层和池化层
flatten and apply a fully-connected layer for
最后扁平化并应用一个全连接层
producing the desired number of class score outputs.
从而生成所需数量的类别分数
After defining a complete CNN,
定义完整的 CNN 后
you can instantiate it and even move it to GPU if it's available.
你可以实例化该模型 如果有 GPU 的话 甚至可以移到 GPU 上
Next, it'll be up to you to specify an appropriate loss and
接下来你需要为此训练任务
optimization function for this training task and finally,
定义合适的损失和优化函数
I've provided a training loop for you.
最后我为你提供了训练循环
You may want to increase the number of epochs you train your final model for.
你可能需要增加最终模型的训练周期数
But this loop will keep track of the training and validation loss as you go.
但是这个循环会跟踪训练和验证损失
If you're validation loss decreases over an epoch,
如果验证损失在某个周期后降低了
your model will be saved.
模型将保存
Then you'll be able to test your train network and see
然后你将能够测试训练过的模型
how it performs on each type of test image.
看看它在每种测试图像上表现如何
The biggest challenge will be defining a complete CNN and as always I encourage you
最大的挑战是定义完整的 CNN
to do your research before you define
像往常一样 我建议你在定义模型之前先查阅资料
your model so that you can make an informed decision as you go.
再做出正确的决策
Try to solve this challenge on your own and if you want to check
请尝试自己完成这道练习
your work next I'll go over one possible solution.
接下来我将介绍一种可能的解决方案供你参考